<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abs-rsses on Belgian Network Research Meeting</title>
    <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abs-rsses on Belgian Network Research Meeting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing dynamic changes of the US financial market: insights from network science</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk10/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;assessing-dynamic-changes-of-the-us-financial-market-insights-from-network-science&#34;&gt;Assessing dynamic changes of the US financial market: insights from network science&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yerali Gandica&lt;sup&gt;1,2,3&lt;/sup&gt;, Marco Geraci&lt;sup&gt;1,3,4,5&lt;/sup&gt;, Sophie Béreau&lt;sup&gt;1,2,6,7&lt;/sup&gt;, Jean-Yves Gnabo&lt;sup&gt;1,2,3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of Namur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; CeReFiM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Namur Center for Complex Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; ECARES&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Université Libre de Bruxelles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; CORE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Université Catholique de Louvain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on the recent and buoyant literature inferring financial interconnectedness from market data by means of various time series techniques [Billio et al. (2012), Diebold and Yilmaz(2015) and Geraci and Gnabo (2016)], we propose in this communication an in-depth analysis of the US financial market and its dynamic, using tools coming from network science. The financial system analyzed consists in a large set of 154 banks, brokers/dealers, insurance and real estate companies listed in the Standard &amp;amp; Poor&amp;rsquo;s 500 index for the period 1993 - 2014.
Looking at the individual, sectoral, community and system wide levels, we show that network science’s tools are able to support well-known features of financial markets such as the dramatic fall of connectivity amid Lehmann Brother collapse. In addition, we also unveil several important new patterns within US financial institutions interconnectedness.
Overall, our results improve our understanding of the US financial landscape and may have important implications for risk monitoring as well as macroprudential policy design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference Using Multi-Channel Regime Switching Information Transfer Estimation</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk09/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;causal-inference-using-multi-channel-regime-switching-information-transfer-estimation&#34;&gt;Causal Inference Using Multi-Channel Regime Switching Information Transfer Estimation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl-Henrik Dahlqvist&lt;sup&gt;1,2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of Namur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Université Catholique de Louvain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past decade has seen the development of new methods to infer causal relationships in biological and socio-economic complex systems, following the expansion of network theory. Nevertheless, the standard estimation of causality still involves a single pair of time dependent variables which could be conditioned, in some instance, on its close environment. However, interactions may appear at a higher level between parts of the considered systems represented by more than one variable. We propose to study these types of relationships and develop a multi-channel framework, in the vein of Barrett and Barnett (Phys. Rev. E, 81 (2010)), allowing the inference of causal relationships between two sets of variables. Each channel represents the possible interaction between a variable of each sub-system. Based on this new framework, we develop two different multi-channel causality measures derived from the usual Granger causality to account for linear interactions and from the concept of transfer entropy for nonlinear contribution. Our measures provide different information about the inferred causal links: the strength of the global interaction between the two sub-systems, the average frequency of the channel switches and the channel contributing the most to the information transfer process for each time step. After having demonstrated the ability of our measures to infer linear as well as nonlinear interactions, we propose an application looking at the U.S. financial sector in order to better understand the interactions between individual financial institutions, as well as parts of the financial system. At the individual level, the considered channels between financial institutions are expressed both in terms of spectral representation using wavelet transform and probability distribution using quantile regressions. Beyond the application presented in the paper, this new multi-channel framework should be easy to implement in other fields of complex system science such as neuroscience, biology or physics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compressing over-the-counter markets</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk02/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;compressing-over-the-counter-markets&#34;&gt;Compressing over-the-counter markets&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tarik Roukny&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Université Libre de Bruxelles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we show that the networked nature of decentralized markets where trading takes place over-the-counter generates excess of notional, i.e., a positive difference between the aggregate gross notional of the market and the minimum aggregate amount satisfying every participants’ net position in the market.
In turn, the existence of this excess makes those markets “compressible”, i.e., the web of outstanding trades can be modified in order to reduce notional excess. We proceed by identifying the different classes of compression and analysing the conditions under which each approach can be applied. We show that a trade-off exists between the amount of excess that can be removed from the market and the conservation of trading relationships. Furthermore, our results highlight the fact that dealers are the prime beneficiaries of compression as their intermediary role is key to the generation of excess. We then show how different initial market structures are affected by compression under different scenarios and discuss the implications. Finally, we apply our theoretical framework to a unique and comprehensive transaction-level dataset on OTC derivatives. First, we find important levels of excess across all references. Second, we show that compression when applied at the global level can reduce a large fraction of these levels of excess. Our results are of interest for both policymakers and market participants as they highlight the mechanics of trades compression and discuss the externatilities at the systemic level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deformed Laplacians on graphs and networks with applications to ranking, visualization and community detection</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk32/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;deformed-laplacians-on-graphs-and-networks-with-applications-to-ranking-visualization-and-community-detection&#34;&gt;Deformed Laplacians on graphs and networks with applications to ranking, visualization and community detection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Fanuel&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Katholieke Universiteit Leuven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many problems related to graphs and networks, like for instance
multiscale community detection or visualization, can be solved by using
the so-called combinatorial Laplacian. Various diffusion processes on
networks are generated by a series of normalized combinatorial
Laplacians, providing efficient tools in many applications. Recently,
several deformations of this discrete Laplacian have been used for
solving a variety of problems in applied mathematics; some important
examples are the signed Laplacian and the connection Laplacian.
Within this context, we propose a class of deformed Laplacians and
discuss their properties in view of applications. Among all the options,
a possible deformation is the dilation Laplacian whose least eigenvector
(i.e., the one of the smallest eigenvalue) can be used to rank objects
from &amp;ldquo;noisy&amp;rdquo; pairwise comparisons; in this problem, the objects are the
nodes of a graph and the comparisons are the directed edges. The nodes
may for instance represent currencies and the edges may be associated to
exchange rates. While still using the dilation Laplacian, we can compute
a ranking of players in sport tournaments, where cyclic inconsistencies
in the comparisons may arise.
Another type of deformed Laplacian is the magnetic Laplacian, which is
complex valued and Hermitian. The least eigenvectors of the magnetic
Laplacian, called the magnetic eigenmaps, can be used in order to
visualize directed networks and to uncover certain types of community
structures in directed graphs.
In this talk, an overview of the construction of such deformed
Laplacians will be given in the light of certain analogies with physical
systems. Several illustrations of potential applications will be outlined.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you believe what you know?  Stereotype learning in the context of social networks</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/poster05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/poster05/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-you-believe-what-you-know-stereotype-learning-in-the-context-of-social-networks&#34;&gt;Do you believe what you know?  Stereotype learning in the context of social networks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia Eberlen&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Olivier Klein&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Matteo Gagliolo&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Université Libre de Bruxelles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Belgians like to drink beer” is a common stereotype in- and outside of Belgium. However, we would be hard-pressed to indicate when we learned about it, as clearly, nobody is born with that knowledge. In addition, knowing about the stereotype is not the equivalent of believing it. We propose that stereotypes are the product of social learning that depends on an individual’s position in a network. We created an agent-based model in order to investigate how people might come to know about stereotypes and are currently implementing the difference between knowledge and endorsement. In the model, agents are connected in a scale-free network generated by the powerlaw cluster graph algorithm (Holme &amp;amp; Kim, 2002) with a clustering coefficient of 0.14. Each node represents one individual who has the ability to learn and remember. The model contains one single stereotype and learning is formalized as purely social. This means that each agent takes into account what it already knows about the stereotype in addition to the stereotype-relevant information presented by its network neighbors.
While what the agent “knows” is a nuanced, continuous stereotype, what its neighbors see is different: from their point of view, the agent will show dichotomous stereotype information, namely whether or not it believes in the stereotype. This reflects people’s shortcomings in presenting their knowledge in a differentiated, nuanced manner, as well as our tendency to simplify and categorize the information surrounding us.
The model is currently being tested in a number of configurations, differing in network structure, allocation of initial biases towards one or another stereotype to the nodes, and parameters of the learning rule. Ultimately, this work will give us further evidence on the impact of network structure on the formation and transmission of stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergent features of triadic relations in political networks</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk28/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;emergent-features-of-triadic-relations-in-political-networks&#34;&gt;Emergent features of triadic relations in political networks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jan Ryckebusch&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Andres M. Belaza&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Kevin Hoefman&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Koen Schoors&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of Ghent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We propose a model with five energy levels that encodes the dynamics of triadic relationships in a political network. The model builds on insights gleaned from structural balance theory to which we add elements from Boltzmann-Gibbs statistical physics and go beyond the restrictions of signed networks. We start from the idea that two agents that maintain ties in a political network can be either enemies, or friends, or neutrals to each other. The generic Hamiltonian associated with the five energy levels contains three parameters. One is connected with a three-body interaction inspired on social balance theory. The other two parameters take into account the costs of symmetry breaking and of changing a link. We stress the role of the degeneracy of the different energy levels and how it affects the degree of frustration in the political network.
The validity of our model is tested on an extended data set for the time series of triadic relationships for the standings between alliances in a massive multiplayer online role-playing game. We also analyze real-world data for the different factions that play a role in the current war in Syria. We find emerging properties in the triadic relationships between the nodes in a political network, for example reflecting itself in a persistent hierarchy between the different energy levels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical household contact networks and their implication for infectious disease spread</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/poster08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/poster08/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;empirical-household-contact-networks-and-their-implication-for-infectious-disease-spread&#34;&gt;Empirical household contact networks and their implication for infectious disease spread&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pietro Coletti&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Niel Hens&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of Hasselt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Airborne infectious diseases such as influenza are primarily transmitted from human to human by means of social contacts and thus easily spread within households. Epidemic models, used to gain insight in infectious disease spread and control, typically rely on the assumption of random mixing within households. Until now there was no direct empirical evidence to support this assumption. In this work, we present the first social contact survey designed to study contact networks within households. The survey was conducted in Flanders in 2010-2011 focusing on households with young children. We analysed data from 318 households totaling 1266 individuals with household sizes ranging from 2 to 7 members.
Exponential-family random graph models (ERGMs) were fitted to the within-household physical contact networks to reveal the processes driving close contact between household members, both on weekdays and weekends. The fitted ERGMs showed a high degree of clustering, with individuals tightly connected within a household and, specifically on weekdays, decreasing connectedness with increasing household size. Furthermore, we found that the odds of a physical contact between father and child is smaller than for any other pair except for older siblings. This supports the findings of te Beest et al. (2014) i.e. pertussis infection of a child by the father or a sibling takes longer than through other pathways.
Epidemic simulations from a discrete-time chain binomial model assuming random mixing within households and using realistic contact networks simulated from the fitted ERGMs, showed only small differences between the two mixing assumptions. Finally, we discuss how the implementation of contact duration may affect the aforementioned picture and we present preliminary results on simulations that take into account the different duration of each contact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning graph-structured dictionaries for sparse representation of diffusive signals on graphs</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk17/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-graph-structured-dictionaries-for-sparse-representation-of-diffusive-signals-on-graphs&#34;&gt;Learning graph-structured dictionaries for sparse representation of diffusive signals on graphs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shuyu Dong&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Université Catholique de Louvain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dictionary learning provides an efficient and flexible way for sparse representation of signals such as natural images. However for signals residing on the vertices of a graph instead of a regular domain, the graph structure of the input space carries important information that an unstructured dictionary may not be able to capture. In order to achieve better adaptability to input signals, it is also desirable to optimise the graph-structured information, which is otherwise predefined in heuristic manners. We address the problem of learning a graph-structured dictionary jointly with the graph for sparse representation of graph signals and propose to design the dictionary using a characteristic diffusion model. Experiments on synthetic and real datasets show that the proposed dictionaries not only have comparable representation performance than unstructured dictionaries but also significantly reduce overfitting of data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Effect on Stock Market Participation</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk21/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;network-effect-on-stock-market-participation&#34;&gt;Network Effect on Stock Market Participation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olga Balakina&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Anastasia Parakhonyak&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Bocconi University, Italy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Toulouse School of Economics, France&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper investigates the effect of social networks on stock market participation in the economy. We study how stock market participation depends on number of informed agents and the intensity of social interactions, while controlling for the wealth distribution. We proceed to compare the performance of different models to estimate the significance of these effects. The impact of social networks on stock market participation is prominent in the empirical evidence of peer effects in the financial literature. We therefore introduce a model of social interaction of agents embedded in a social network and study diffusion of information about an entrance and operating on the stock market. In the model each agent faces fixed participation costs depending on agent type, professional and non-professional. We assume that non-professional agent has high participation cost due to lack of information about the stock market. The cost for non-professional agent is decreasing in the number of informed neighbors who provide information to their friends. We provide an algorithm for finding an equilibrium stock market participation for a particular network structure and use Danish registry data for the period 2010&amp;ndash;2013 to test our hypothesis of the connectivity affecting the stock market participation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIS Epidemics and the Direction of Information Flow in Brain Networks</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk30/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;sis-epidemics-and-the-direction-of-information-flow-in-brain-networks&#34;&gt;SIS Epidemics and the Direction of Information Flow in Brain Networks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jil Meier&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Delft University, The Netherlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The  interplay  between  structural  connections  and  emerging
information flow in the  human brain remains an  open research problem.  A
recent study observed global patterns  of directional information flow  in
empirical data using the measure of transfer entropy. For higher frequency
bands, the overall  direction of  information flow was  from posterior  to
anterior regions whereas an anterior-to-posterior pattern was observed  in
lower frequency bands.  In this study,  we applied a  simple SIS  epidemic
spreading model  on  the human  connectome  with  the aim  to  reveal  the
topological properties of the structural  network that give rise to  these
global patterns.
In order to quantify the information flow between regions, we computed the
transfer entropy  values  for all  node  pairs evaluating  different  time
windows. We  found  that  direct  structural  connections  induced  higher
transfer entropy  between  two brain  regions  and that  transfer  entropy
decreased with increasing distance between nodes (in terms of hops in  the
structural network). Applying the SIS model,  we were able to confirm  the
empirically observed opposite information flow patterns, which seem to  be
linked to different time scales  of the spreading process. Posterior  hubs
in the structural network  appear to play a  dominant role in the  network
dynamics  since  the  global  pattern  of  information  flow  is  in   the
posterior-to-anterior direction when these hubs are strong senders, and in
the opposite  direction  when  they are  strong  receivers.  Our  analysis
suggests that these  global patterns of  directional information flow  are
the result of  an unequal  spatial distribution of  the structural  degree
between posterior and anterior regions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shareholding network of financial institutions: a dynamic analysis</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk12/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;shareholding-network-of-financial-institutions-a-dynamic-analysis&#34;&gt;Shareholding network of financial institutions: a dynamic analysis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyrille Dossougoin&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Donald Zountcheme&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Université Catholique de Louvain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade interconnectedness has become key to characterize the
financial system and to analyze phenomena that can jeopardize its stability.
Financial institutions are involved in many transactions like lending and
borrowing contracts, syndicated loans, international capital flows and
cross-holdings to list a few. All these transactions create complex linkages
among them
which, in case of downfall of an institution, can result in bad
outcomes for the real economy as materialized in the recent financial crisis.
Therefore to strengthen policy interventions, tools from the network
literature are used to study the architecture of financial systems. We
contribute to this ongoing debate by analyzing the topology of
cross-shareholding network of financial institutions (banks, insurance
companies, broker-dealers etc.). For this we exploit portfolio holdings data
of 82 large financial institutions located in United States and Europe over
the period 2006-2012. We are able to study the changes in the network
structure through time and thus complement common works on static interbank
networks. Furthermore we use network based measures to quantify the level of
integration and diversification of each financial institutions. Integration
refer to the level of exposure of financial institutions to each other and the
diversification captures how the cross-shareholding is spread out. Our results
show that as time passes the cross-shareholding network becomes dense and
exhibit a scale free property. In addition some financial institutions tend to
keep their levels of integration and diversification stable while for others
those factors decrease mainly after the financial crisis in 2008. These
findings offer new insights on the systemical importance of financial
institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sovereign Wealth Funds&#39; cross-border investments: assessing the role of country-level drivers and spatial competition</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk13/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;sovereign-wealth-funds-cross-border-investments-assessing-the-role-of-country-level-drivers-and-spatial-competition&#34;&gt;Sovereign Wealth Funds&amp;rsquo; cross-border investments: assessing the role of country-level drivers and spatial competition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malik Kerkour&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Jean-Yves Gnabo&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Nicolas Debarsy&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of Namur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; CNRS, France&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of this paper is to identify the driving forces of cross-border investments emanating from Sovereign wealth funds and to test the existence of spatial competition among recipient countries. For this, we develop an original econometric framework that quantifies the role of spatial dependence in the location of investments, and that uses a modified version of the standard estimation procedure of spatial panel model, which accommodates the Inverse Hyperbolic Sine transformation of the dependent variable. This transformation copes with two critical features of net capital flows, namely an highly skewed distribution and the presence of zero and negative values. Using a large-scale database, we provide evidence of negative spatial dependence, investments in one country being on average at the expense of its neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stationarity of the inter­event power­law distributions</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/poster11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/poster11/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;stationarity-of-the-inter-event-power-law-distributions&#34;&gt;Stationarity of the inter­event power­law distributions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yerali Gandica&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Joao Carvalho&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, Fernando Sampaio Dos Aidos&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, Renaud Lambiotte&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, Timoteo Carletti&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of Namur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Universidade de Coimbra, Portugal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of human activities exhibit a bursty pattern, namely periods of very high activity that are followed by rest periods. Records of these processes generate time series of events whose inter­-event times follow a probability distribution that displays a fat tail. The grounds for such phenomenon are not yet clearly understood.
In this communication we will present some results concerning the use the freely available Wikipedia’s editing records to unravel some features of this phenomenon. We will show that even though the probability to start editing is conditioned by the circadian 24 hour cycle, the conditional probability for the time interval between successive edits at a given time of the day is independent from the latter. We confirm our findings with the activity of posting on the social network Twitter.
Our result suggests there is an intrinsic humankind scheduling pattern: after overcoming the encumbrance to start an activity, there is a robust distribution of new related actions, which does not depend on the time of day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Model for Information Propagation in Complex Networks</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/talk16/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;stochastic-model-for-information-propagation-in-complex-networks&#34;&gt;Stochastic Model for Information Propagation in Complex Networks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dimitri Papadimitriou&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Alcatel Lucent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most information propagation models in complex networks are probabilistic as they rely on the probability that vertices interact only locally with their neighbors. In this paper, we propose a stochastic propagation model that takes into account uncertainty in drift and diffusion. For this purpose, we consider the motion of information as being driven by an uncontrolled state process {X(t): t &amp;gt; 0}. The probability density function u(x,t) associated to this state process represented by the random variable X(t) satisfies the so-called Fokker-Planck (a.k.a. Kolmogorov forward) equation. The equation governing the information propagation model by combining drift and diffusion collectively defines thus a convective propagation phenomena. Our computational method makes use of polynomial chaos expansions (PCE) that enable to compactly represent the variable of interest as a linear combination of orthogonal polynomials which depend on another continuous random variable z (with known distribution). The latter characterizes uncertainty in model parameters (the drift and diffusion coefficients), input and output variables. The solution u(x,t,z) can thus be represented as a truncated series of orthogonal polynomials multiplied by deterministic coefficients. The dimension of the resulting system of coupled non-linear partial differential equations grows with the order of the polynomial chaos expansion and the dimension of the stochastic input. The resolution of this system of partial differential equations, realized using Matlab produces a propagation pattern that accounts for the convective effects induced by medium- and long-distance interactions (thus, beyond local interactions). Moreover, since various interactions between information yield delays which may alter the propagation dynamics due to the so-called memory effect (future behavior of the state process depends not only on the present but also on former states), we further explore propagation models where the governing equation is formulated by the nonlinear stochastic delay-differential equation (SDDE) also referred to as Stochastic Differential Equations with Memory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/graham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2016/abs/graham/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tba&#34;&gt;TBA&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bryan S. Graham&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; University of California, Berkeley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>