<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Belgian Network Research Meeting</title>
    <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Belgian Network Research Meeting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://be-net.github.io/2019/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Location and Contact</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/location-and-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/location-and-contact/</guid>
      <description>Location The BeNet 2019 meeting will be held at University of Hasselt, campus Diepenbeek building D, room c21. Registration will take place at the entrance of building D.
Address: Agoralaan gebouw D, 3590 Diepenbeek, Belgium
 Directions From Hasselt station you can take buses 45, 36 and 20A and get off at the second stop inside the campus (Directions)
Contacts For any question or request please contact Pietro Coletti</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/program/</guid>
      <description>Schedule 10:00 - Registration and welcome
10:10 - Maxime Lucas, Aneta Stefanovska and Duccio Fanelli - Synchronisation in nonautonomous networks of oscillators
10:30 - Wouter Devos and Daniele Marinazzo - Synchronisation on structural connectivity brain networks
10:50 - Benjamin Chiêm, Frédéric Crevecoeur and Jean-Charles Delvenne - A control-theoretic framework to understand how structural brain networks can flexibly support various functional states
11:10 - Coffee break
11:30 - Daniele Marinazzo and Sebastiano Stramaglia - Synergy and redundancy from the network perspective</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/registration/</guid>
      <description>Important dates  Abstract submission Extended deadline 16.02.2019 (both oral and poster contributions) Notification of acceptance 18.02.2019 Registration 19.02.2019  Call for abstracts Oral and poster contribution are welcome, please refer to EasyChair for submissions.
Oral contributions: : short talks abstracts (20 minutes including questions) should be submitted via EasyChair.
Poster contributions: : submit the abstract via EasyChair (please append the word [POSTER] to the title of your submission).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk 01</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/talk-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/talk-01/</guid>
      <description>Test</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>