<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Belgian Network Research Meeting</title>
    <link>https://be-net.github.io/2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Belgian Network Research Meeting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://be-net.github.io/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2017/</guid>
      <description>BeNet &amp;ndash; What? The 7th edition of the Belgian Network Research Meeting (BeNet) will be held at the University of Ghent (UGent) on December 6th, 2017.
This annual meeting is a place for the Belgium-based researchers interested in the network paradigm to meet and communicate their results, regardless of the discipline: biology, communication, economics, geography, history, informatics, mathematics, medicine, physics, sociology, statistics, etc.
Previous editions were held in Louvain-La-Neuve (UCL 2016), Namur (UNamur 2015), Brussels (ULB 2014), Leuven (IIS/KUL 2013), Antwerpen (UA 2012) and Brussels (VUB 2011).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location and Contact</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2017/location-and-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2017/location-and-contact/</guid>
      <description>Location The BeNet 2017 meeting will be held at Ghent University, in leslokaal Paddenhoek 1.0, Aula Complex (https://soleway.ugent.be/routes/2114l).
Address: Paddenhoek 1-3, 9000 Ghent.

Contacts For any question or request please contact Daniele Marinazzo or Julie Birkholz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2017/program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2017/program/</guid>
      <description>You can download the book of abstract from HERE.
Program  8:30 Welcome and Registration 9:00 Econometric Models of Network Formation   Bryan S. Graham   Invited Speaker  10:00 Coffee Break 10:30 Compressing Over-The-Counter Markets Tarik Roukny  10:50 Network Effect on Stock Market Participation Olga Balakina, Anastasia Parakhonyak  11:10 Assessing Dynamic Changes of the US Financial Market: Insights from Network Science Yerali Gandica, Marco Geraci, Sophie Béreau, Jean-Yves Gnabo  11:30 Sovereign Wealth Funds&amp;rsquo; Cross-border Investments: Assessing the Role of Country-level Drivers and Spatial Competition Malik Kerkour, Jean-Yves Gnabo, Nicolas Debarsy  11:50 The Belgian Production Network Glenn Magerman, Emmanuel Dhyne  12:10 Lunch + Poster session 13:10 Mixing Event 14:00 Causal Inference Using Multi-Channel Regime Switching Information Transfer Estimation Carl-Henrik Dahlqvist  14:20 Learning Graph-structured Dictionaries for Sparse Representation of Diffusive Signals on Graphs Shuyu Dong  14:40 Stochastic Model for Information Propagation in Complex Networks Dimitri Papadimitriou  15:00 Deformed Laplacians on Graphs and Networks with Applications to Ranking, Visualization and Community Detection Michael Fanuel  15:20 Coffee Break 15:50 The Impact of Business Location on University Contract Research: a Two-mode ERGM Analysis André Spithoven, Jef Vlegels, Walter Ysebaert  16:10 Emergent Features of Triadic Relations in Political Networks Jan Ryckebusch, Andres M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2017/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2017/registration/</guid>
      <description>Important dates  Abstract submission  Tue, Nov 21, 2017 (both oral and poster contributions) Notification of acceptance  Sat, Nov 25, 2017  Registration  Fri, Dec 1, 2017   Call for abstracts Oral and poster contribution are welcome, please refer to EasyChair for submissions.
 Oral contributions: short talks abstracts (20 minutes including questions) should be submitted to EasyChair in text format (no more than 300 words).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>