<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Belgian Network Research Meeting</title>
    <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Belgian Network Research Meeting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://be-net.github.io/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Location and Contact</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/location-and-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/location-and-contact/</guid>
      <description>Location The BeNet 2019 meeting will be held at University of Hasselt, campus Diepenbeek building D.
Address: Agoralaan gebouw D, 3590 Diepenbeek, Belgium
 Directions From Hasselt station you can take buses 45, 36 and 20A and get off at the second stop inside the campus (Directions)
Contacts For any question or request please contact Pietro Coletti</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/program/</guid>
      <description>Schedule 09:30 - Jérôme Kunegis, Pawan Kumar, Jun Sun and Giuseppe Pirrò - SynGraphy: Succinct Summarisation of Large Networks via Small Synthetic Representative Graphs
09:50 - Malbor Asllani and Timoteo Carletti - Topological resilience in non-normal networked systems
10:10 - Leto Peel - Beyond networks: Incorporating node metadata into network analysis
10:30 - Coffee break
11:00 - Yerali Gandica, Marco Valerio Geraci, Sophie Béreau and Jean-Yves Gnabo - Financial institutions’ vulnerability: assessing the role of intra and inter-community dependences</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/registration/</guid>
      <description>Important dates  Abstract submission 10.02.2019 (both oral and poster contributions) Notification of acceptance 14.02.2019 Registration 15.02.2019  Call for abstracts Oral (20 minutes, including questions) and poster contribution are welcome.
Registration Registration is free. Nonetheless the space is limited. Preference will be given to people presenting some work, and promotion of diversity will be a criterion of choice. Please register by 15.02.2019. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t plan to submit a oral/poster contribution, you can register by simply sending an empty abstract with the word [REGISTRATION].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk 01</title>
      <link>https://be-net.github.io/2019/talk-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://be-net.github.io/2019/talk-01/</guid>
      <description>Test</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>